You can't prepare for where the truth will take you.
8MM is a thriller, crime, mystery film directed by Joel Schumacher.
A small, seemingly innocuous plastic reel of film leads surveillance
specialist Tom Welles down an increasingly dark and frightening path.
With the help of the streetwise Max, he relentlessly follows a bizarre trail
of evidence to determine the fate of a complete stranger.
As his work turns into obsession, he drifts farther and farther away
from his wife, family and simple life as a small-town PI.
Tom Welles, played by Nicolas Cage.
Max California, played by Joaquin Phoenix.
Eddie Poole, played by James Gandolfini.
Dino Velvet, played by Peter Stormare.
Longdale, played by Anthony Heald.
Machine, played by Chris Bauer.
8mm is a 1999 crime thriller film directed by Joel
Schumacher and written by Andrew Kevin Walker.
A German–American co-production, the film stars Nicolas Cage as a private
investigator who delves into the world of snuff films.
Joaquin Phoenix, James Gandolfini, Peter Stormare, and
Anthony Heald appear in supporting roles.
Despite being selected for the Golden Bear and receiving standing ovations from audiences at the Berlin International Film
Festival, the film received mostly negative reviews from critics due to its excessively violent and disturbing content.
However, it was a moderate box office success.
The film explores themes of new york city, pornography,
underground, loss of loved one, sex shop.
The tone is mind_bending and dark and intense.